hey guys so this is a fun geometry
problem right here we have four circles
and the area of all four of these
circles is 144 pi and they tell us that
the radius of these smaller circles is x
the radius of this medium circle is 3x
and the radius of this larger circle is
5X and I want us to solve for x first
the area of a single circle is pi r
squared so if we're going to add four
circles we're going to be adding up four
pi r squareds we're going to set this
sum equal to 144 Pi because that was
given as the area of the four circles
for this first Circle that'll be the top
one we'll plug in X for R and for the
second Circle let's do this bottom one
so we'll plug in X for the radius for
the third circle let's plug in 3x for
the radius now we're going to plug in 5x
for the last one since everything is
multiplied by pi independently and we
have an equation we can divide both
sides by pi and I'll just get rid of all
of our Pi's so then let's bring down the
144 this would just be x squared this is
just x squared but then 3x squared the 3
is going to get a squared and the x is
going to get a squared so that's going
to be 9x squared and this case is the 5
good squared as well as the X so we get
25 x squared we can bring down the 144
again now we're going to combine like
terms all of these are X squareds so
we're ultimately just going to add the
coefficients 1 plus 1 plus 9 plus 25
gives us 36 x squared so we can divide
both sides by 36 144 divided by 36 is 4
and this right hand side the 36 is
cancel to give us x squared to solve for
x we square root both sides square root
of 4 is 2 and the square root of x
squared is X now we don't have to worry
about plus or minus 2 because you can't
have a negative value in a geometry
problem like this so this is the answer
to the question x equals two